# RAJU CHOUDHARY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+977 9805339366

**Q** Biratnagar - 3

razoo.choudhary@gmail.com

https://rajuchoudhary.com.np

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a skilled Full Stack Web Developer experienced in creating efficient web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP. I have a strong understanding of working with databases like MySQL and Rest APIs. I am committed to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and continuously improving my skills.

## **EDUCATION**

London Metropolitan National Examination Board

B.Sc. Hons in computing +2 Science

2019-2022 2015-2017
First Class Honors First Division

## **EXPERTISE**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery PHP, NodeJS, Laravel and TypeScript SQL Database and Redis API, Git and GitHub

## **EXPERIENCE**

Sajilo Software Solutions Current

Sr. Full Stack Web Developer

Best Nepal Pvt. Ltd. 2022 - 2023

Mid - Full Stack Web Developer

I have experience working on three e-commerce projects in Hong Kong, including Asisatees, Boomracing, and Teamraffeeco. I also worked on a project called Advisebridge, as well as an in-house PHP library for payment integration with Himalayan Bank and Nabil Bank.

## Tech Community Nepal 2021 - 2022

Mid - Full Stack PHP Developer

I have developed an in-house e-commerce project and worked on multiple client-based projects. In addition, I have experience working with Rest APIs.

## Tech Community Nepal 2021 - 2021

Internship in Web Development

I completed an internship from July to September 2021, where I gained experience working with PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, and JS.

## **SOCIAL LINKS**







## **PROJECTS**

## Iconify (Browser Extension)

## Source Code

An Browser Extension that allows you to download premium Lottie, and SVG Icons from Premium Icon Library Sites for free.

## DB-Builder (PDO for PHP)

#### Source Code

Fast, efficient, and useful Query Builder and PDO Class for #PHP (Faster than Eloquent Model)

## R-Drive (Cloud Storage)

#### Demo Link

R-Drive is a cloud-based storage solution that has been developed using React and Laravel. The system boasts a Redis-based cache system, making it highly efficient and powerful, while also delivering fast performance.

## Ry-Store (Ecommerce)

#### Demo Link

Ry-Store is an E-commerce platform that offers a Multi Vendor system with advanced features such as AI-based Product Recommendations and a WebSocket Chat System. Made using PHP Core Library